Register of the Walter Henry Judd papers
Hoover Institution Archives
- CONGRESSIONAL FILE, 1924-1983 (Box 61-156)
  - General
    - House of Representatives
      - House Administration Committee, 1946-1962 (Box-folder 110: 5)
        Correspondence. Includes material relating to printing, national emblems, and a congressional chapel.
      - Interior and Insular Affairs Committee, 1945-1962 (Box-folder 110: 6-7)
        Includes the former Committees on Mines and Mining, National Parks, Lands and Indian Affairs. Correspondence. Includes material relating to Hawaiian and Alaskan statehood, water projects, environmental conservation and wilderness lands, and minerals.
      - Interstate and Foreign Commerce Committee, 1945-1962 (Box-folder 112: 1-4, Box-folder 111: 1-6)
        Correspondence. Includes material relating to freight rates, railroad retirement programs, medical and scientific research, alcoholic beverages, natural gas, transportation, fluoridation of water, aviation, and broadcasting.
      - Judiciary Committee
        - General, 1954-1959 (Box-folder 112: 5)
          Reports (including J. Edgar Hoover), memorandum, and draft legislation. Includes material relating to immigration and displaced persons, racial discrimination, corrections, congressional salaries, communism, and the Bricker amendment.
        - Correspondence, 1943-1962 (Box-folder 114: 1, Box-folder 112: 6, Box-folder 113: 1-4)
      - Merchant Marine and Fisheries Committee, 1945-1962 (Box-folder 114: 2)
        Correspondence. Includes material relating to wildlife conservation and compensation.
      - Post Office and Civil Service Committee, 1945-1962 (Box-folder 114: 3-6, Box-folder 115: 1-5, Box-folder 116: 1-4)
        Correspondence. Includes material relating to salary increases, postal rates, and the census.
      - Public Works and Transportation Committee, 1944-1962 (Box-folder 116: 5, Box-folder 117: 1-2)
        Includes the former Rivers and Harbors and Public Buildings and Grounds Committees. Correspondence and a newsletter. Includes material relating to water projects (such as the St. Lawrence Seaway) and highway construction.
      - Rules Committee, 1945-1962 (Box-folder 117: 3)
        Resolutions, statements, reports, memorandum, correspondence, newsletter, and clippings. Includes material relating to states, procedures, and investigations.
      - Science and Aeronautics Committee, 1959-1962 (Box-folder 117: 4)
      - Small Business Committee, 1945-1959 (Box-folder 117: 5)
        Memoranda, draft legislation, report, and correspondence.
      - Un-American Activities Committee
        - General, 1948-1956 (Box-folder 117: 6)
          Statements, press releases, newsletter, and clippings. Primarily relates to student protests in San Francisco and the film "Operation Abolition."
        - Correspondence, 1945-1973 (Box-folder 117: 7)
      - Veterans' Affairs Committee, 1945-1962 (Box-folder 118: 1-4, Box-folder 117: 8)
        Correspondence. Includes material relating to pensions and other benefits.
      - Ways and Means Committee, 1945-1962 (Box-folder 118: 5-6, Box-folder 123: 1-2, Box 119-122)
        Correspondence. Includes material relating to trade agreements, taxation, social security, medical, and welfare programs.
    - Library of Congess, 1946-1980 (Box-folder 123: 3)
    - Senate, 1945-1961 (Box-folder 123: 4)
      Correspondence relating to legislation and Senate committees.
  - Agriculture
    - General, 1941-1961 (Box-folder 123: 5)
      Correspondence, press releases, proposed legislation, memoranda, statements (including Ezra T. Benson), regulations, and printed matter.
    - Food and Agriculture Act of 1962, 1961-1962 (Box-folder 123: 6)
      Draft legislation, printed matter, newsletters, correspondence, and memoranda. Primarily relates to price supports.
  - Antarctic, 1950-1959 (Box-folder 123: 7)
    Correspondence and press release.
  - Atlantic Union
    - General, 1949-1960 (Box-folder 124: 1)
      Primarily correspondence. See also: General/Legislation/81st Congress and 83rd Congress and General/Trips/1951 November.
    - Atlantic Union Committee, 1949-1966 (Box-folder 124: 2)
      Printed articles, correspondence (including Joseph McCarthy, John Stennis, Jacob Javits, and other Congressional colleagues), resolutions, draft policy statement, notes, and statements (including Estes Kefauver).
  - Atomic energy and arms control
    - General, 1945-1963 (Box-folder 124: 3)
      Correspondence (including Norman Cousins, Christian Herter, Christopher Emmet, and Hubert Humphrey) and notes.
    - Atomic Energy Act of 1946, 1946-1962 (Box-folder 124: 4)
      Correspondence, draft legislation, notes, memorandum, printed matter, and a speech (Bernard Baruch). Includes material relating to the Atomic Energy Commission.
    - Arms Control and Disarmament Act of 1961, 1961-1963 (Box-folder 124: 5)
      Draft legislation, reports, printed matter, hearing transcripts, pamphlets, memorandum, and correspondence. Includes material relating to the Arms Control and Disarmament Agency.
  - Austria, 1953-1958 (Box-folder 124: 6)
    Correspondence and a memorandum.
  - Aviation, 1944-1960 (Box-folder 124: 7)
    Correspondence (includes a copy of a letter from Franklin Roosevelt) and a report.
  - Britain, 1946-1970 (Box-folder 124: 8)
    Correspondence, statement, clippings, and a newsletter. Primarily relates to loans.
  - Burma, 1949-1969 (Box-folder 125: 1)
    Memorandum, printed articles, clippings, and correspondence. Includes material relating to communism and U Nu.
  - Ceylon, 1955 (Box-folder 125: 2)
    Correspondence (Ambassador R.S.S. Gunewardene) and a speech.
  - Civil rights, 1944-1962 (Box-folder 125: 3-5)
    Correspondence (including Roy Wilkins, and Clarence Mitchell), printed matter, newsletters, speeches and statements, reports, notes, draft legislation, and press releases. Includes Dr. Judd's record on civil rights legislation and material relating to the Fair Employment Practices Act (including a bill introduced by Dr. Judd in the 80th Congress).
  - Congo (Katanga)
    - General, 1961-1967 (Box-folder 125: 6)
      Notes, printed matter, newsletters, statements (including Moises Tshombe, Thomas Dodd, G. Mennen Williams, and Strom Thurmond), report, press releases, and advertisements. Includes material relating to the American Committee for Aid to Katanga Freedom Fighters.
    - Correspondence, 1961-1968 (Box-folder 125: 7)
      Includes a copy of a message from Moises Tshombe to President Kennedy.
  - Cuba, 1957-1969 (Box-folder 125: 8-9)
    Clippings, resolutions, report, statement, memoranda, notes, and correspondence (including Lawrence O'Brien, the Consejo Revolucionario de Cuba, and telegrams from Dr. Judd to President Kennedy).
  - Cyprus, 1954-1956 (Box-folder 126: 1)
  - Czechoslovakia, 1947-1955 (Box-folder 126: 2)
    Correspondence and clippings. Includes material relating to the Karol Folta espionage case.
  - Defense
    - General, 1953-1958 (Box-folder 126: 3)
      Memoranda, letter, and chart. Includes material relating to the National Guard and the Joint Chiefs of Staff.
    - Inter-American Military Cooperation Act, 1947 (Box-folder 126: 4)
      Meeting report, notes, draft legislation, clippings, press releases, statements (including Harry Truman, George Marshall, and Matthew Ridgway), newsletters, and memoranda.
    - National Security Act of 1947, 1945-1953 (Box-folder 126: 5)
      Speech, draft and final legislation, press releases, clippings, charts, report, and correspondence (including James Forrestal and Charles M. Cooke).
    - Status of Forces treaty, 1953-1957 (Box-folder 126: 6)
      Notes, statements, reports, resolutions, and correspondence. Relates to the issue of criminal jurisdiction over U.S. forces in international defense alliances.
    - Universal Military Training, 1947-1953 (Box-folder 126: 7)
      Newsletter and correspondence (including Wilson Compton).
  - Economics
    - General, 1945-1954 (Box-folder 126: 8)
      Clippings, pamphlet, reports, statement, correspondence, and miscellany. Includes material relating to inflation and the 1948 special session of Congress.
    - Office of Price Administration, 1942-1946 (Box-folder 126: 9)
      Correspondence, press releases, notes, newsletters, printed matter, reports, copies of legislation, and statements.
  - Education
    - General
      Draft legislation, speeches and statements, printed matter, notes, memoranda, reports, pamphlets, bulletins, press releases, and a memorandum to President Eisenhower from Walter Judd. Primarily relates to proposed federal legislation to aid for scholarships and classroom construction.
      - 1943-1956 (Box-folder 126: 10)
      - 1957-1962 (Box-folder 127: 1-2)
    - Correspondence, 1944-1962 (Box-folder 127: 3)
      Includes form letters from congressional colleagues.
  - Europe, 1946-1972 (Box-folder 127: 4)
    Correspondence, report, resolutions, press release, speech (John F. Kennedy), and printed matter. Includes material relating to Italy and the Council of Europe.
  - Foreign aid
    - General, 1951-1963 (Box-folder 127: 5)
      Printed articles, newsletters, pamphlets, notes, clippings, correspondence (including the ECA), reports, charts, and memoranda. Includes material relating to criticisms of aid programs.
    - Aid to Greece and Turkey (PL 75), 1946-1949 (Box-folder 127: 6)
      Reports, correspondence, statements and speeches (including Harry S. Truman, Dean Acheson, Henry F. Grady, and Harry Byrd), draft and final copies of legislation, hearing summaries, press releases, notes, newsletter, clippings, and abstracts.
    - Joint Resolution providing post-war relief (PL 84), 1947 (Box-folder 128: 1)
      Statement (Harry S. Truman), draft and final copies of legislation, resolutions, notes, reports, correspondence, and a pamphlet.
    - Foreign Aid Act of 1947 (PL 389) (Box-folder 128: 2)
      Reports, draft and final copies of legislation, correspondence, resolutions, and notes. Includes a telegram in support of aid to China, signed by William Bullitt, Josephus Daniels, and others.
    - Economic Assistance Acts, general, 1947-1952 (Box-folder 128: 3)
      Correspondence (including Hubert Humphrey, Walter Robertson, Karl Compton, Helen Loomis, Paul Hoffman, and various individuals and groups interested in China). Includes the European Recovery Program (Marshall Plan) and aid to China.
    - Foreign Assistance Act of 1948 (PL 472), 1947-1977 (Box-folder 128: 4)
      Draft and final copies of legislation, reports, memoranda, speeches and statements (including Harry S. Truman), notes, newsletters, press releases, resolutions, and clippings.
    - Foreign Assistance Act Extension, 1947-1950 (Box-folder 128: 5-6, Box-folder 129: 1)
      Press releases, speeches and statements (including Paul Hoffman), draft and final copies of legislation, memoranda, reports, charts, clippings, hearing transcripts, and notes. Includes material relating to a proposed amendment to provide military aid to China.
    - Mutual Defense Act of 1949, 1949-1953 (Box-folder 129: 2)
      Statements (including Harry S. Truman), notes, reports, draft and final legislation, radio broadcast transcripts (Walter Trohan), printed matter, and correspondence.
    - Act for International Development of 1950 (Point Four Program), 1949-1956 (Box-folder 129: 3-4)
      Includes reports, clippings, hearing summary, draft legislation, statements (including Harry S. Truman), pamphlet, notes, newsletters, memoranda, and correspondence.
    - Mutual Security Program, 1951-1960 (Box-folder 129: 5-6, Box 130-132)
      Statements (including Nelson Rockefeller, Dean Acheson, Arthur Radford, Dwight Eisenhower, Jacob Javits, and John Foster Dulles), reports, draft and final copies of legislation, memoranda, budget charts, outlines, press releases, debate transcripts, printed matter, clippings, notes, and correspondence. Correspondents include George Marshall, the State Department, the Mutual Security Agency, Jacob Javits, Philippine President Magsaysay, Harold Stassen, Alexandra Tolstoy, Alfred Kohlberg, the Ceylonese Ambassador R.S.S. Gunewardene, the Defense Department, the Indian Ambassador G.L. Mehta, the White House, Douglas Dillon, John Sherman Cooper, Thomas Dodd, and John Vorys to John Foster Dulles. Includes material relating to Arab and Israeli resettlement and surplus agricultural commodities.
    - Aid to communist countries, 1960-1963 (Box-folder 133: 1-2)
      Printed matter and correspondence (including William F. Buckley). Includes material relating to an article in the National Review citing Dr. Judd's position.
    - Agency for International Development (AID), 1961-1969 (Box-folder 133: 3)
      Correspondence (including Chester Bowles and AID officials), speech, press releases, clipping, and a report.
    - Peace Corps Act of 1961, 1959-1976 (Box-folder 133: 4-5)
      Correspondence (including R. Sargent Shriver, Bill Moyers, and Nicholas Katzenbach), chart, reports, clipping, memoranda, draft legislation, budget, newsletter, and notes. Includes material on the activities of a precursor program, International Voluntary Services, Inc., in Southeast Asia.
    - Foreign Assistance Act of 1961 (Box-folder 134: 1-3)
      Reports, correspondence (including Dean Rusk, Dwight Eisenhower and Nelson Rockefeller), draft legislation, clippings, debates, notes, budget charts, and press releases.
    - Organization of Economic Cooperation and Development, 1961 (Box-folder 134: 4)
    - Foreign Assistance Act of 1962, 1961-1962 (Box-folder 135: 1, Box-folder 134: 5)
      Debates, reports, draft legislation, notes, memoranda, form letters, newsletter, statements (including Dean Rusk), and correspondence (including the AFL-CIO and Dean Rusk). Includes material relating to a congressional trip to Korea, Vietnam, and Turkey.
  - Germany, 1943-1973 (Box-folder 135: 2-3)
    Correspondence (including Christopher Emmet), printed matter, resolutions, newsletters, reports, statements (including Elbridge Durbrow), and memoranda.
  - Greece, 1941-1970 (Box-folder 135: 4)
    Correspondence, resolutions, the statement of a communist partisan, notes, printed matter, and press releases.
  - Housing and urban development
    Pamphlets, correspondence (including the AFL), clippings, notes, press releases, reports, draft and final legislation, statements, newsletters, flyers, and a chronology. Relates to legislation, the establishment of a cabinet-level department, and rent control.
    - 1945-1949 (Box-folder 135: 5-6)
    - 1950-1962 (Box-folder 136: 1)
  - Hungary, 1948-1965 (Box-folder 136: 2)
    Correspondence, printed matter, newsletter, and statements (including Roscoe Drummond and Jozsef Koevago, Mayor of Budapest).
  - Immigration and refugee relief
    - General, 1948-1962 (Box-folder 136: 3)
      Notes, correspondence, press releases, newsletter, statements, clipping, and miscellany. Includes material relating to the World Refugee Year.
    - Cases
      Requests for individual assistance from Dr. Judd. Includes numerous Chinese refugees.
      - General, 1945-1962 (Box-folder 136: 4-5, Box-folder 137: 1-4)
      - Alphabetic
        Correspondence (including the State Department and the Immigration and Naturalization Service), forms, printed matter, relief bills, affidavits and other legal documents, photographs, and miscellany.
        - A (Box-folder 137: 5)
        - B-C (Box-folder 138: 1-7)
        - D-J (Box-folder 139: 1-4)
        - K-L (Box-folder 140: 1-4)
        - M-S (Box-folder 141: 1-5)
        - T-Z (Box-folder 142: 1-3)
    - Legislation
      - General, 1943-1960 (Box-folder 142: 4-5)
        Relief bills, regulations, reports, clippings, and correspondence.
      - Displaced Persons Act of 1948, 1947-1951 (Box-folder 142: 6)
        Abstracts, clippings, notes, statements, draft and final copies of legislation, letters, and regulations. Includes material relating to U.S. participation in the International Refugee Organization.
      - Immigration and Nationality Act of 1952, 1952-1960 (Box-folder 143: 1)
        Draft and final copies of legislation, printed articles, statements, newsletters, debates, press release, and correspondence. Primarily relates to proposed amendments.
      - Refugee Relief Act of 1953, 1953-1957 (Box-folder 143: 2)
        Reports, statements, letter, draft and final copies of legislation, and notes.
  - India
    - General, 1942-1980 (Box-folder 143: 3-6)
      Clippings, pamphlets, miscellany, notes (including a conversation between Dr. Judd and President Radhakrishnan), hearing transcript, background material and itinerary (for 1953 trip?), reports, Indian newspapers, memoranda, newsletters, press releases, printed matter, and correspondence. Correspondents include Jacob Javits, Edward Carter of the Institute for Pacific Relations, George Allen, Robert Chiperfield, Everett Drumright, and Chester Bowles. Includes material relating to Kashmir, foreign aid to India, Krishna Menon, Jawaharlal Nehru, and Indian neutrality.
    - Food aid, 1951 (Box-folder 144: 1-3)
      Flyer, open letter from a congressional group to Harry Truman, press releases, speeches and statements (including Harry S. Truman, Jawaharlal Nehru and Walter Reuther), a pamphlet, and correspondence (including Jack McFall and Jacob Javits).
  - Indonesia, 1949-1982 (Box-folder 144: 4)
    Correspondence, statement, and printed matter.
  - Ireland, 1950-1954 (Box-folder 144: 5)
    Correspondence and pamphlet. Relates to legislation in support of re-unification.
  - Japan
    - General, 1937-1969 (Box-folder 144: 6-8)
      Clippings, memoranda, conference materials, press releases, a copy of a letter and a statement by John Foster Dulles, a speech by Dwight Eisenhower, reports, a newsletter, printed articles, notes, a treaty text, miscellany, and correspondence (including Joseph Grew, Norman Thomas, Thruston Morton, and Japanese officials). Relates to politics, trade relations, World War II, and the peace treaty conference.
    - Ryukyu Islands (Okinawa), 1952-1969 (Box-folder 145: 1-2)
      Correspondence, memoranda, reports, printed articles, and notes. Includes material relating to a group of immigrants to Bolivia.
  - Korea
    - General, 1945-1959 (Box-folder 146: 1, Box-folder 145: 3-5)
      Statements (including Henry Cabot Lodge, Jr. and Syngman Rhee), reports, notes (including meetings with Rhee and other Korean officials), flyer, press release, a telegram sent by Dr. Judd to Dean Acheson (?), newsletter, printed matter, and correspondence (including Thruston Morton, Syngman Rhee and other Korean officials, Alexander Smith, William Knowland, and other Congressmen).
    - American Korean Foundation, 1953-1958 (Box-folder 146: 2)
      Correspondence, statement (Milton Eisenhower), report, and miscellany.
    - Economic aid, 1945-1957 (Box-folder 146: 3)
      Correspondence (including Korean officials), printed articles, clippings, press release, statements (including Syngman Rhee and Harry S. Truman), draft and final legislation, reports (including Albert C. Wedemeyer), chronology, and newsletters.
    - Prisoners of war, 1952-1954 (Box-folder 146: 4)
      Correspondence, clippings, press releases, statements (including Henry Cabot Lodge, Jr.), notes, memoranda, and texts of peace agreements. Primarily writings of and correspondence with Christopher Emmet.
  - Labor
    - General, 1935-1963 (Box-folder 146: 5-6)
      Notes, draft and final copies of legislation, clippings, reports, resolutions, pamphlets, debates, newsletters, printed articles, AFL convention proceedings, charts, statements (including John Kennedy), and correspondence primarily related to strikes (including Gabriel Hauge, the AFL-CIO, Arthur Watkins, and an open letter from a group of Congressmen to Harry Truman).
    - Full employment bill, 1931-1946 (Box-folder 147: 1)
      Speeches and statements, notes, printed articles, newsletter, draft legislation, reports, debate transcripts, clippings, and a leaflet.
    - Case anti-strike bill, 1946 (Box-folder 147: 2)
      Notes, newsletter, copies of bills, statements, debates, legislative summaries, clippings, report, and printed articles.
    - Labor Management Relations Act (Taft-Hartley Act)
      - General, 1947-1948 (Box-folder 147: 3)
        Correspondence, abstracts, clippings, pamphlets, legislative summaries, draft and final copies of legislation, press releases, statements (including Richard M. Nixon), newsletters, reports, and flyers.
      - Proposed amendments (Wood and Lesinski bills), 1949-1954 (Box-folder 147: 4)
        Statements (including Richard M. Nixon), legislative summaries, clippings, draft and final copies of legislation, correspondence, notes, reports, newsletters, and miscellany.
    - Labor-Management Reporting and Disclosure Act
      - Kennedy-Ives bill, 1958-1959 (Box-folder 147: 5)
        Reports, miscellany, legislative summaries, newsletters, flyers, notes, press releases, correspondence, debates, statements, and clippings.
      - Landrum-Griffin Act, 1958-1962 (Box-folder 148: 1)
        Report, statements, draft legislation, newsletters, debate transcripts, and correspondence.
    - Manpower Development and Training Act, 1961-1962 (Box-folder 148: 2)
      Draft legislation, report, and correspondence.
  - Laos, 1955-1970 (Box-folder 148: 3)
    Correspondence (including Christopher Emmet, J. Graham Parsons, and Laotian officials), clippings, statement, and notes.
  - Latin America and the Caribbean, 1949-1963 (Box-folder 148: 4)
    Memoranda and correspondence (including the White House, William Macomber, Jr., and Harold Geneen). Includes material relating to foreign aid, Mexico, Colombia, Guatemala, and Brazil.
  - Loyalty-security issues
    - General, 1948-1961 (Box-folder 148: 5)
      Correspondence, a memorandum with cover letter from Richard Nixon, and an executive order with a statement by Dwight Eisenhower. See also: SUBJECT FILE/Communism and anti-communism; CONGRESSIONAL FILE/State Department/Foreign policy; and CHINA FILE/United States/State Department.
    - McCarthy, Joseph, 1950-1984 (Box-folder 148: 6)
      Correspondence, pamphlet, speeches and statements, newsletter, book review, clippings, interview, report, and printed articles.
  - MacArthur, Douglas, 1945-1972 (Box-folder 148: 7)
    Correspondence, clippings, printed articles, statements, broadcast transcripts, report, campaign material, and miscellany. Includes material relating to his dismissal by President Truman.
  - Medicine
    - General, 1962 (Box-folder 148: 8)
    - Compulsory health insurance, 1944-1949 (Box-folder 148: 9, Box-folder 149: 1)
      Pamphlets, newsletters, clippings, statements, printed articles, reports, abstracts, flyers, miscellany, and letters. Includes material generated by the American Medical Association.
    - Conscription of health workers, 1950-1955 (Box-folder 149: 2)
      Correspondence, notes, clipping, statements, draft and final copies of legislation, newsletters, and telegrams.
    - Medicare, 1958-1962 (Box-folder 149: 3)
      Memoranda, report, draft legislation, printed matter, correspondence, newsletters, resolutions, press release, and speeches.
  - Middle East
    - General, 1946-1975 (Box-folder 149: 4)
      Report, resolutions, memorandum, advertisements, notes, newsletters, chronology, printed matter, and a speech transcript. Relates to United Nations policy and the partition of Palestine, the Suez Crisis, foreign aid, refugees, Egypt, Iran, Turkey, Arab-Israeli conflict, and U.S. troops in Lebanon.
    - Correspondence, 1943-1962 (Box-folder 150: 1-2, Box-folder 149: 5-6)
      Includes Jacob Javits, Robert Hill and other State Department officials, Donald R. Heath, and United Arab Republic officials.
  - Mongolia, 1946-1961 (Box-folder 150: 3-5)